Ali Sarkeshik

San Diego, CA 92122 Cell: (949)-466-2546 AliSarkeshik@gmail.com

Solutions-driven Full Stack Developer/Software Engineer who uses ingenuity and creativity to build fluid and functional web applications. My previous experience includes method development in Chemistry and Instrumentation (hardware and software troubleshooting) in a resale and OEM environment.

Education

UCSD Coding Bootcamp Full Stack Development San Diego, CA February 2019 - Present

- Learning front-end and back-end technologies through a dynamic curriculum.
- ➤ Technologies include HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Java, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Database Theory, Bookshelf.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Command Line, and Git.
- Click here for a list of my projects and to learn more about me

University of California, Riverside. Bachelor of Science, Chemistry

Work History

Perkin Elmer Customer Support Engineer - Diagnostics San Diego, CA June 2018 - December 2018

- ➤ Provided on-site personalized support services for PerkinElmer instruments
- Provided troubleshooting expertise and repair skills needed to help identify and resolve issues related to hardware, software or applications support.
- ➤ Performed PMs, installs, and repairs on various Perkin Elmer instruments (Janus and EuroImmun products).

Roche Diagnostics Planned Activities Specialist/Field Service Engineer Contract Position via Tailored Management San Diego, CA **January 2018 - May 2018**

- ➤ Performed on-site preventative maintenance, installation, and technical updates (TSB's) on company products (Cobas 6000 and 8000 analyzers).
- ➤ Diagnosed mechanical, hardware, software and system failures
- ➤ Trained in: CD Foundations of Hardware, IT Products, c6000/8000 Service Operator Training, and Cobas 6000 Install/Core Service

BioSurplus, Inc. Service Engineer San Diego, CA **January 2017 - July 2017**

> Determined the re-sale viability of company acquisitions.

- > Diagnosed, repaired, and serviced a wide range of laboratory equipment.
- ➤ Systems included but were not limited to: Flow Cytometry (BD FacsCalibur, Luminex 100 and 200), Centrifuges (Beckman Coulter, Sorvall, Eppendorf), Refrigeration systems (Cold Freezers and Incubators), Automated Liquid Handlers (Tecan Evo Freedom), Mass Spectrometry (Agilent, Shimadzu, Thermo), HPLC (Agilent 1100/1200), and GC (Agilent 6850/6890).

Versum Materials (Formerly Air Products and Chemicals, Inc) November 2013 – January 2017 Analytical Chemist Contract Position via The Fountain Group: November 2013 – May 2015 Carlsbad, CA

- > Supported the lead analytical researcher responsible for the analysis and verification of high purity chemicals.
- > Worked closely with a team of researchers to support method development for new products.
- Performed hands on installation (hardware/software), calibrations, troubleshooting, and maintenance on GC instruments (Agilent 5973/6850/6890/Thermo Trace 1310).
- ➤ GC-TCD/GC-FID, GC-MS, DIP-MS analysis of organo silanes and GC-PHID analysis of Octane
- Successfully assisted in transitioning R&D products to commercial status (ISO: 9001:2008, 17025, 10012)
- Performed Karl Fischer titrations to determine water content of sample submissions.

British Petroleum - Bio Fuels Research Associate Contract Position via Collabera San Diego, CA March 2013 - October 2013

- Performed hands on installation (hardware/software), calibrations, troubleshooting, and preventative maintenance on HPLC (Agilent 1100/1200 series), GC (Agilent 5975 MSD/6890N/7890A GC), and IC (Metrohm IC 818-819) chromatographic instruments
- SEC-HPLC Analysis of: Organic Acids, Sugars, Oligomers, Solids, and Furans in Fermentation and Yeast engineering Samples
- IC Analysis of Organic Acids
- Headspace GC Analysis and Method Development of Ethanol, Isobutanol, Isobutyl Acetate, and Ethyl Acetate in Fermentation Samples

Ionis Pharmaceuticals (Formerly ISIS Pharmaceuticals) October 2012 – November 2012 Research Associate/Scientist - Oligo Synthesis Contract Position via Aerotek Carlsbad, CA

- > Production of synthetic oligonucleotides (using Mermade 192 synthesizer) in a GLP environment
- ➤ Analytical techniques used: C5 and C8 SAX purification (GE AKTA Explorer) and C7 Desalt (GE AKTA Avant)
- ➤ Utilized Agilent 6130 Quadrople LC-MS to verify fraction purity

The Scripps Research Institute
Department of Chemical Physiology
Research Technician
Advisor: John R. Yates III, PhD
La Jolla, CA

July 2006 – July 2011

Research Technician for the Yeast Resource Center (YRC) - A Biomedical Technology Resource Center supported by grants from NIH and the NCRR located at the University of Washington at Seattle. In conjunction with scientists around the world, successfully identified and sequenced protein structures in a variety of organisms (human, yeast, worm, etc) through the utilization of various analytical chemistry (Mass Spectrometry, HPLC, etc), cell biology (protein purification), and Bioinformatic techniques (Linux based programming, database searches, etc) techniques. From these experiments gene expression and function were studied so as determine their effects upon human health.

- Performed hands installation (hardware/software), calibration, troubleshooting, and preventative maintenance on LC/LC-MS (LTQ and LTQ Orbitrap) and HPLC instruments (Agilent 1100)
- ➤ Protein characterization and data analysis by Mass Spectrometry (MS) of over 1000 protein complexes (Using Agilent 1100 RP-HPLC, LTQ and LTQ Orbitrap)
- Successfully co-authored over 30 publications with foreign and domestic collaborators
- > Technical editing and writing experience: construction and implementation of new YRC SOPs, coauthoring scientific publications, creation and maintenance of YRC protocol and instrumentation webpage
- ➤ Database maintenance, creation, and modification for YRC Public Data Repository
- > Successfully improved YRC data processing system (Data submission, database parsing, etc)

List of Publications: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed?term=sarkeshik